Hawaii, we have a problem!
Lilo & Stitch 2: Stitch Has a Glitch is a animation,
family, comedy film directed by Michael LaBash.
Now, we find the rowdy extraterrestrial getting
used to life with his new ʻohana.
However, a malfunction in the ultimate creation of Dr.
Jumba soon emerges, which reinstates his destructive programming and threatens to
both ruin his friendship with Lilo and to short him out for good!
Stitch (voice), played by Chris Sanders.
Lilo Pelekai (voice), played by Dakota Fanning.
Nani (Voice), played by Tia Carrere.
Dr. Jumba Jookiba (voice), played by David Ogden Stiers.
Pleakley (voice), played by Kevin McDonald.
Kumu (voice), played by Kunewa Mook.
Lilo & Stitch is a 2025 American science fiction comedy film
produced by Walt Disney Pictures and Rideback.
Directed by Dean Fleischer Camp, it is a live-action animated remake of
Disney's 2002 traditionally animated film Lilo & Stitch.
The film stars Sydney Elizebeth Agudong, Billy
Magnussen, Hannah Waddingham, Courtney B.
Vance, Zach Galifianakis, and Maia Kealoha in her film debut, with original Lilo &
Stitch writer-director Chris Sanders reprising his voice role as Stitch.
Development on a live-action remake of Lilo & Stitch began in October 2018, with
writer Mike Van Waes and producers Dan Lin and Jonathan Eirich attached.
By November 2020, Jon M.
Chu was in talks to direct, while Van Waes left the
project despite still being credited.
Fleischer Camp and Chris Kekaniokalani Bright were announced as the film's new director and writer
respectively in July 2022, with casting taking place between November 2022 and June 2023.
Principal photography ran from April to July 2023, filming during the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike until suspending
production due to the 2023 SAG-AFTRA strike, and then in February and March 2024 after both strikes ended.
Dan Romer composed the score, and Industrial Light & Magic provided the film's
visual effects with the assistance of several other effects houses.
Lilo & Stitch premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on May 17, 2025, and was
released in the United States on May 23, by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and grossed $1.038 billion, becoming the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2025 and
the highest-grossing live-action/animated hybrid in history, being the first of its kind to gross over $1 billion.
A sequel is in development, with Sanders returning as writer.
The film explores themes of hawaii, alien, glitch, native hawaiian.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.